Just because you’re accepted doesn’t mean you belong.
School Ties is a drama film directed by Robert Mandel.
When David Greene receives a football scholarship to a prestigious prep school in the 1950s, he feels pressure to hide
the fact that he is Jewish from his classmates and teachers, fearing that they may be anti-Semitic.
He quickly becomes the big man on campus thanks to his football skills, but when his Jewish background is discovered,
his worst fears are realized and his friends turn on him with violent threats and public ridicule.
David Greene, played by Brendan Fraser.
Charlie Dillon, played by Matt Damon.
Chris Reece, played by Chris O'Donnell.
Rip Van Kelt, played by Randall Batinkoff.
McGivern, played by Andrew Lowery.
Jack Connors, played by Cole Hauser.
School Ties is a 1992 American drama film directed by Robert Mandel and starring Brendan Fraser, Matt Damon,
Chris O'Donnell, Randall Batinkoff, Andrew Lowery, Cole Hauser, Ben Affleck, and Anthony Rapp.
Fraser plays the lead role as David Greene, a Jewish high school student who is awarded an
athletic scholarship to an elite preparatory school in his senior year.
The film explores themes of scholarship, sports,
massachusetts, coming of age, judaism.
The tone is dark and emotional.